<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Emergency Application</string>
    <string name="title_activity_navigation_drawer">NavigationDrawer</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_open">Open navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_close">Close navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="nav_header_title">Green Archers Emergency Application</string>
    <string name="nav_header_subtitle">android.studio@android.com</string>
    <string name="nav_header_desc">Navigation header</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>

    <string name="menu_home">Home</string>
    <string name="menu_trusted_contacts">Trusted Contacts</string>
    <string name="menu_government_hotlines">Government Hotlines</string>
    <string name="menu_siren_flicker">Siren And Flicker Light</string>
    <string name="menu_about">About</string>
    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="Intro_storm">Ang bagyo ay isang uri ng lagay ng panahon na nagdudulot ng malakas at mabilis na hangin at pag-ulan na maaring maging sanhi ng matinding pagbaha, daluyong ng dagat at pagguho ng mga lupa.</string>
    <string name="Intro_storm_surge">Ang storm surge o daluyong ng dagat ay ang pagtaas ng tubig-dagat sanhi ng bagyo.</string>
    <string name="Intro_earthquake">Ang lindol ay ang pagyanig ng lupa dahil sa biglaang paggalaw ng mga bato sa ilalim nito.</string>
    <string name="Intro_flood">Ang baha ay pag-apaw ng sobra-sobrang tubig sa natural nitong daluyan tulad ng sapa, ilog, at dagat dahilan upang malubog ang nakapalibot ditong lupa.</string>
    <string name="Intro_landslide">Ang landslide o pagguho ay ang pagbaba ng lupa, bato, putik, at iba pang bagay mula sa mataas na lugar. Ito ay maaring mangyari kapag may malakas at tuloy-tuloy na pag-ulan o pagyanig mula sa lindol.</string>
    <string name="Intro_volcanic">Ang pagputok ng bulkan ay nangyayari kapag nagbuga ang bulkan ng mga bato, lava, abot, at mga usok.</string>
    <string name="Intro_fire_disaster">Ang mga sunog ay banta ng panganib sa kaligtasan ng tao at ng kaniyang mga ari-arian at kabuhayan. Mahalaga na may kaalaman ukol sa pag-iwas sa sunog at mga dapat gawin sakaling magkasunog.</string>
    <string name="Intro_goBag">Kapag may banta ng panganib, kailangan lumikas papunta sa higit na ligtas na lugar.  Bilang paghahanda sa mga ganitong pagkakataon, mahalaga na may GO BAG na dadalhin ang pamilya.</string>
    <string name="Intro_animal_bites">Rabies is a deadly viral infection that is mainly spread by infected animals. It can be transmitted through close contact with infected saliva via bites or scratches from rabid animals like dogs.</string>
    <string name="Intro_cpr">Cardiopulmonary resuscitation (CPR) can help save a life during a cardiac or breathing emergency. However, even after training, remembering the CPR steps and administering them correctly can be a challenge. In order to help you help someone in need, we\'ve created this simple step-by-step guide that you can print up and place on your refrigerator, in your car, in your bag or at your desk.</string>
    <string name="step_2_cpr">Call 911 for assistance. If it\'s evident that the person needs help, call (or ask a bystander to call) 911, then send someone to get an AED. (If an AED is unavailable, or a there is no bystander to access it, stay with the victim, call 911 and begin administering assistance.)</string>
    <string name="step_1_cpr">Check the scene and the person. Make sure the scene is safe, then tap the person on the shoulder and shout Are you OK? to ensure that the person needs help.</string>
    <string name="rule_3_cpr">Open the airway. With the person lying on his or her back, tilt the head back slightly to lift the chin.</string>
    <string name="rule_4_cpr">Check for breathing. Listen carefully, for no more than 10 seconds, for sounds of breathing. (Occasional gasping sounds do not equate to breathing.) If there is no breathing begin CPR.</string>
    <string name="cpr_redcross_rule_1">Push hard, push fast. Place your hands, one on top of the other, in the middle of the chest. Use your body weight to help you administer compressions that are at least 2 inches deep and delivered at a rate of at least 100 compressions per minute.</string>
    <string name="cpr_redcross_rule_2">Deliver rescue breaths. With the person\'s head tilted back slightly and the chin lifted, pinch the nose shut and place your mouth over the person\'s mouth to make a complete seal. Blow into the person\'s mouth to make the chest rise. Deliver two rescue breaths, then continue compressions. Note: If the chest does not rise with the initial rescue breath, re-tilt the head before delivering the second breath. If the chest doesn\'t rise with the second breath, the person may be choking. After each subsequent set of 30 chest compressions, and before attempting breaths, look for an object and, if seen, remove it.</string>
    <string name="cpr_redcross_rule_3">Continue CPR steps. Keep performing cycles of chest compressions and breathing until the person exhibits signs of life, such as breathing, an AED becomes available, or EMS or a trained medical responder arrives on scene. Note: End the cycles if the scene becomes unsafe or you cannot continue performing CPR due to exhaustion.</string>
</resources>